<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://martynguyen64.github.io/Martins-Blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://martynguyen64.github.io/Martins-Blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-02-27T01:02:48-06:00</updated><id>https://martynguyen64.github.io/Martins-Blog/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Marty the Beast</title><subtitle>Marty's blogging site with Jupyter Notebooks !!! :)</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Python NBA Quiz</title><link href="https://martynguyen64.github.io/Martins-Blog/python/2023/02/26/quizzes23.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Python NBA Quiz" /><published>2023-02-26T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2023-02-26T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://martynguyen64.github.io/Martins-Blog/python/2023/02/26/quizzes23</id><author><name></name></author><category term="Python" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[NBA Quiz]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Marty uses JavaScript</title><link href="https://martynguyen64.github.io/Martins-Blog/javascript/2023/02/26/javascript.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Marty uses JavaScript" /><published>2023-02-26T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2023-02-26T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://martynguyen64.github.io/Martins-Blog/javascript/2023/02/26/javascript</id><author><name></name></author><category term="Javascript" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Chapter 7 Bio Notes</title><link href="https://martynguyen64.github.io/Martins-Blog/2023/02/26/Chapter-7-bio-notes.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Chapter 7 Bio Notes" /><published>2023-02-26T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2023-02-26T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://martynguyen64.github.io/Martins-Blog/2023/02/26/Chapter-7-bio-notes</id><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Natural Selection]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Create a Performance Task Writeup</title><link href="https://martynguyen64.github.io/Martins-Blog/markdown/2023/02/25/NOTMt2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Create a Performance Task Writeup" /><published>2023-02-25T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2023-02-25T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://martynguyen64.github.io/Martins-Blog/markdown/2023/02/25/NOTMt2</id><author><name></name></author><category term="markdown" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Writeup a.i. The point of this program is to allow users to store their diets within their name; they can store diets by naming them and inputting the macros and the ntoes of the diet.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://martynguyen64.github.io/Martins-Blog/images/logo.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://martynguyen64.github.io/Martins-Blog/images/logo.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">5.5 - 5.6s Blog Post</title><link href="https://martynguyen64.github.io/Martins-Blog/markdown/2023/02/13/53thru56review.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="5.5 - 5.6s Blog Post" /><published>2023-02-13T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2023-02-13T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://martynguyen64.github.io/Martins-Blog/markdown/2023/02/13/53thru56review</id><author><name></name></author><category term="markdown" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[5.5 Legal and Ethical Concerns License Communities, License Types Guide When you create a GitHub repository it requests a license type. Review the license types in relationship to this Tech Talk and make some notes in your personal blog. Software licenses and options are agreements that specify how users may use, distribute, and modify software. The most typical software licenses include MIT, GNU, etc. With GNU, anyone can access your material for free. Blog discussions and personal analysis of software licenses/options, digital rights, and other legal and ethical considerations from this College Board topic. Software licenses and options are agreements between software creators and users that determine how the software can be used, distributed, and modified. Make a license for your personal (blog) and Team repositories for the CPT project. Be sure to have a license for both Team GitHub repositories (frontend/backend). Document license(s) you picked and why. FYI, frontend, since it is built on GitHub pages may come with a license and restrictions. Document in blog how team made license choice and process of update. My own personal blog puts the repository under the open source GPL license. We also made the group repository license an open source GPL license. We chose this license because we want the code to be open to everyone, but we don’t allow anyone to redistribute the closed source code. 5.6 Safe Computing Describe PII you have seen on project in CompSci Principles. Some Personal Identifiable Information that I have seen on github is names, emails, photos, education, and for some, birth date, addresses and phone numbers. What are your feelings about PII and your personal exposure? Due to PII, I think you should be careful about what you post online. It’s okay to share names and email addresses, but you shouldn’t share anything personal like social security numbers or passwords. But this his PII helps companies tailor their own his website to our interests and increase the popularity of their own his website. Describe good and bad passwords? What is another step that is used to assist in authentication. A good password is long, contains numbers and special keys, and is completely irrelevant to the user. Another step you can use for authentication is two-factor authentication by sending an email. Try to describe Symmetric and Asymmetric encryption. Symmetric encryption means that a private key encrypts and decrypts information. Asymmetric cryptography uses two keys, a public key and a private key, to encrypt and decrypt information. Provide an example of encryption we used in AWS deployment. An example of encryption we used in AWS deployment is the SSL encryption. And this uses both the symmetric and the asymmetric encryption. Describe a phishing scheme you have learned about the hard way. Describe some other phishing techniques. Most phishing emails I receive end up in spam, so I haven’t learned the hard way about phishing schemes. However, when I saw the email, it turned out to be a phishing scam. But a friend of mine got hacked on Discord and he sent me the file and I almost clicked on it. Some phishing techniques send emails pretending to be from large companies. Also by hacking the user’s account and sending the link to anyone they know.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://martynguyen64.github.io/Martins-Blog/images/logo.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://martynguyen64.github.io/Martins-Blog/images/logo.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>